Guide to the American Left Ephemera Collection, 1875-2015 AIS.2007.11
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Communists and Civil Liberties, VI.
  Communists used three primary rhetorical approaches to seek public support in their battles against prosecution and harassment. First, they argued that their espousal of revolution was open and public, not conspiratorial, and purely rhetorical. Indeed, they vigorously opposed individual acts of violence, such as the bombings as "propaganda of the deed" advocated by some anarchists. None of the indictments against them, they pointed out, cited any specific violent acts. Second, they argued that they were a legitimate political party, functionally equivalent to the Democratic and Republican Parties. Finally they argued that harassment of Communists for their controversial views threatened the civil liberties of all Americans and stifled public discussion and thought. The first two defenses were probably valid descriptions of the frame of mind and intentions of the bulk of rank and file Communists, but prosecutors had no trouble demonstrating that Communist propaganda had frequently advocated violent revolution in the past and the necessity of revolutionary violence was a central contention of core Marxist-Leninist texts. Moreover, prosecutors had evidence (though they sometimes hesitated to present it in open court for fear of revealing details of the intelligence apparatus) that Party leaders and dozens of Party members had participated in Soviet espionage. The Communists' third argument—that anticommunist repression stifled civil liberties and public discourse for non-Communists was true—but Communists found that liberals who they expected to support their defense on such grounds frequently refused to do so not only because of fear that they too would thereby invite harassment on themselves, but also because the Communists' long history of sudden shifts in their public positions and vitriolic sectarian denunciations of political competitors had fundamentally undermined Communists' credibility.
  - Treason in Congress, The Record of the Un-American Activities Committee, by Albert E. Kahn (Box 1, Folder 205)
  - The Schneiderman Case, United States Supreme Court Opinion with an Introduction by Carol King, August 1943 (Box 1, Folder 206)
  - Documents Regarding Harry F. Ward from the Committee to Investigate Un-American Activities (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hearings Before the Committee on Un-American Activities, House of Representatives, Eighty-Fifth Congress, First Session, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Democracy, Civil Rights and Liberty in Connecticut, by Daniel Howard, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Mine Mill Conspiracy Case, by Sidney Lens (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Democracy Should Begin At Home" (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - America's Thought Police, October 1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Happy Birthday" Postcard Issued by the National Conference to Win Amnesty for Smith Act Victims (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Freedoms and Foreign Policy, by Owen Lattimore (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Amnesty!, by Marion Bachrach, December 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - What Everyone Should Know About the "Bill of Rights" and other Constitutional Guarantees of Individual Freedom, A Scriptographic Study Unit, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Censored News Of Your America, Will America Become a Land of Whispers?, September 1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Citizens Without Rights (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - What Kind of Teachers for your Child, The Facts Behind the Suspension of 8 Excellent Teachers, May 1950 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Right to Travel, by Corliss Lamont, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Case of the Stubborn Editor (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Note of Resignation to the Belamy Club from Edith Rickard (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "A Dangerous Woman", Stella Petrosky Held for Deportation, by Sprad, June 1936 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - What Political Prisoners Do We Defend? Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Bill of Rights in Danger!, by Robert W. Dunn, January 1940 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Civil Liberties in the U.S.A., A Short History of the Origin and Defense of the Bill of Rights, by S. Small (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Big Plot, Proof of the Justice Department's Plan to Jail 21, 105 Americans (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fellow Citizens: Our husbands are in prison!... (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Digest of Amicus Curiae Brief to the United Supreme Court on the Constitutionality of the Internal Security Act of 1950 in the case of Communist Party of the U.S.A. v. Subversive Activities Control Board (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Twelve and You, What Happens to Democracy is your business, too!, by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - "Is This What Truman Means By Civil Rights!" (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Due Process in a Political Trial, The Record vs. The Press (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Reign of Witches, The Struggle Against the Alien and Sedition Laws, by Elizabeth Lawson, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Red Tape and Barbed Wire, by Sender Garlin, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - In Danger, The Right to Speak for Peace, by Harold Spencer (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "The Persecution of Oleta O'Connor Yates" (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Patriotism against McCarthyism (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - "Turn Informer or Go to Jail! Which Choice Would You Make?, Oleata O'Connor Yates Made Hers!" (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Books on Trial, The Case of Alexander Trachtenberg, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Greet the New Year with the L.A. Committee for Protection of Foreign Born (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - "Summary and Analysis of Important Features of the Alien Registration Act of 1940, Smith Act", November 3, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - "Supreme Court of the United States" Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - The Case of Carl Marzani (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - "It Can Happen to You" Flyer (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Jailed for Fighting Franco, Free Them!" (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "In the Supreme Court of the United States, October Term, 1948, No. ........" (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "The 13th Juror, The Inside Story of My Trial, A Dramatic Revelation", by Steve Nelson (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - "S.F. No. 16,935 In the Supreme Court of the State of California" (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 600 Prominent Americans Ask President to Rescind Biddle Decision, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - The Walter- McCarran Law, Extracts From Testimony Before President's Commission on Immigration & Naturalization (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Man Bites Dog, Report of an Unusual Hearing before the McCarran Committee (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - The People Vs. McCarthyism, The Case Against the McCarran Act, by John Abt (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Mandel Vs. McCarthyism (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Only the People Can Decide (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Rights, Un-American Activities Committee Acts Unconstitutionally, October 1959 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Report of the Subcommittee on Constitutional Rights of the Committee on Judiciary Pertaining to Loyalty Oaths, March 1959 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Hate Groups and the Un-American Activities Committee, by David Wesley, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - For Abolition of the Inquisitorial Committees of Congress (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "When Conscience Speaks" (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "The Bill of Rights and The Mundt-Ferguson Bills", An Analysis of the Provisions and Opinion on their Constitutionality (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Vengeance of the Young, The Story of the Smith Act Children, by Albert E. Kahn, June 1952 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - The People's Case, The Story of the IWO, by Albert E. Kahn, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Creeping McCarthyism: Its Threat to Church, School and Press, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - The Crime Against Jean Field, by Albert E. Kahn, February, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Is a Fair Trial Possible at the Hands of Federal Juries (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Scholar and School- New Targets for Bigotry (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Shall Freedom of Speech Apply to all Americans? (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Not Guilty!, The Case of Claude Lightfoot, June 1955 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - The Strange Trial of Stanley Nowak, by Conrad Komorowski, December 1954 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - McCarthy on Trial, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "Remove the Dagger! From the Heart of the Bill of Rights" (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Elizabeth Bentley and Her Role in the Attack on the New Deal (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "Defend the Bill of Rights Rally" Flyer (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - An Open Letter to the American People (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Morton Sorbell, Prisoner on Our Conscience, A Newspaper to Secure Justice in the Case of Morton Sorbell, November 1956 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Supreme Court of the United States, October Term, 1952, No. 687, Julius Rosenberg and Ethel Rosenberg vs. United States of America (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Flyer Instructing Communists to Take Action Against Los Angeles City Councilman Davenport (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Exile, The Story of David Hyun (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Scholar and School- New Targets for Bigotry (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Why Did They Fire My Teacher? (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - In the Shadow of Liberty, The Inhumanity of the Walter- McCarran Law, by Abner Green, September 1954 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Can Americans Tolerate Prison for Ideas? Pamphlet with Accompanying Letter, April 1954 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - "Journal for 1956, Published for the 6th Annual Conference to Repeal the Walter-McCarran Law and Defend its Victims", April 7, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - End Exile (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - "An Open Letter to the American People" (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - The Rape of the First Amendment, by Alexander L. Crosby (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Free American's from the McCarran Act Danger!, by Gus Hall (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - End McCarrasnism on this we Stand Together (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - The McCarran Act, Fact and Fancy, by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - "...And What Can We Say to Gus Polites?, We Need a Statute of Limitation!" (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - "Facts and Opinions McCarran Internal Security Act" Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - "Rules and Procedures for the Walk for the Bill of Rights" Flyer (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - "Defend Academic Freedom: Stop McCarthyism Now!", A Statement on Academic Freedom Week by the Labor Youth League (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Burlington Dynamite Plot, by Walt Pickard (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Letters from the Tombs, by Morris U. Schappes, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - The Case of Claude Lightfoot (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - We Accuse McCarthyism, February 1954 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - The Heat is On! (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Loyalty Oath, If We Remain Silent... (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Smear and Run...An Un-American Activity (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Who's Unamerican!, July 1947 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - "CRC Monthly News Letter Exclusively for CRC Member", November 1950 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - "Let Freedom Ring for Earl Browder", by Carl Ross, February 1942 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - "Earl Browder Takes His Case to the People", January 1940 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - "An Open Letter to J. Howard McGrath", Attorney General of the United States, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Elizabeth Gurley Flynn Speaks to the Court, Opening Statement to the Court and Jury in the Case of the Sixteenth Smith Act Victims in the Trial at Foley Square, New York, July 1952 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - "The Smith Act", New Conspiracy Against American Labor (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Report on the Denial of Labor and Civil Rights in Hudson County, New Jersey, February 1937 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - A Letter to Congress: Defeat the Anti-Labor Smith Bill!, by William Z. Foster, June 1952 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - The Smith ...McCarran...Taft-Hartley Conspiracy to Strangle Labor, by George Morris, October 1951 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - The Smith Act- A Threat to Labor (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - "It is Later Than You Think..." A Solemn Warning and Appeal to the People of Los Angeles County! (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - 13 Communists Speak to the Court, March 1953 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - McCarthyism and the Big Lie, by Milton Howard, November 1953 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Courage is Contagious, The Bill of Rights versus The Un-American Activities Committee, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Either the Constitution or the Mundt Bill, America Can't Have Both!, by Simon W. Gerson, June 1950 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - In Defense of the Communist Party and the Indicted Leaders, by William Z. Foster, July 1949 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - "Don't Let it Happen Here", A Call to the American People (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - "Communists Trial Defendants Join Picket Line" Photograph, June 7 1949 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - The Twelve and You, What Happens to Democracy is Your Business, too!, by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, September 1948 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - "To Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case" Pamphlet, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - "An Appeal for Clemency" Pamphlet, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Mercy for the Rosenbergs Flyer, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - "Fact Sheet in the Rosenberg Case" Pamphlet, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - "The Nelson Case: State Sedition Laws are Weapons of Anti-Labor, Anti-Negro, Anti-Semitic Repression" Leaflet, May 1955 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - "Defend Academic Freedom! A Statement on Academic Freedom Week by the Labor Youth League" Pamphlet, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Rights, V.1 N.10, June 1954 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - McCarthyism in the Courts: the story of the Steve Nelson Frame-up Pamphlet, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - "Constitution of the International Labor Defense" (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Ten Years of Labor Defense, by Sasha Small, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Labor Research Association's Monthly Labor Notes, August 1938 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Night Riders in Gallup, by Louis Colman, May 1935 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - Friedel Rosenthal, U.S. Hostage in Germany, by James C. Bilotta with Accompanying Letter from the Author (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - We Want Drastic Revision or Outright Repeal of the Racist & Discriminatory Walter-McCarran Law By the 85th Congress!, April 6, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - "Fight the Blacklist!" Flyer (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - "Conference of Inquiry", Source Material for Panel Discussion (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - "Happy 50th Birthday George Black Charney" Postcard (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - "An Open Letter To and About Alger Hiss", 1966 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - "Special International Tribunal on the Violation of Human Rights of Political Prisoners of War in United States Prison and Jails", 1990 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - "On Dec. 26, 1948 Carl Winter Spoke and Jimmy Zarichny Listened" (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - "They Gave Their Freedom!" Rose Baron, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - "The Individual and the State: The Problem as Presented by the Sentencing of Roger N. Baldwin", November 1918 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - "American Deportation and Exclusion Laws" Report, January 1919 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - "The Frightened Giant" Cedric Belfrage, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - "The Right of Asylum" Charles Recht, 1935 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - "The Communist Trial: An American Crossroads" George Marion, 1949 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - "Smith Act Trial Reports" 26 Issues, April 1952- January 1953 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - "Letters From Prison" Eugene Dennis, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - "If You Have Nothing to Hide..." Kentuckians Against KUAC, 1968 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Important Actions of UE's 13th International Convention, 1948 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Union Book Club Flyer, ca. 1940s-1950s (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - "Their Offense: Fighting For The People!" Flyer, 1951 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - "One Step Leads to Another..." Booklet (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - "What's a Mugwump?" Flyer (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - "A Law to Gag and Control the American People" Pamphlet (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - UE Flyers (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - "Here's How it Works - From Official United States Government Documents" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - "Why Politicians Red-Bait" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - "What Are They Really After?" Booklet (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Flyer protesting proposed anti-communist LA ordinance, 1950 (Box 38, Folder 15)
- Communist Party USA (CPUSA), VII.
  The Communist Party U.S.A., successor to the multiple left-wing factions that split off from the Socialist Party U.S.A. at its 1919 convention, did not develop significant influence until the mid-1930s. While they initially commanded at least nominal support of perhaps 70,000 of the SPUSA's 110,000 members, that support drifted away as the rival Communist factions operated as secret undergrounds and refused to cooperate. The Comintern pressured them to combine into as an open political party, the Workers Party of America, in 1922, but they maintained a dual underground structure for several years thereafter, and continued factional squabbles. Ultimately the Party only achieved working unity between 1927 and 1929 by expelling the significant portions of the leadership who identified with Stalin's factional rivals in the Soviet Party. The Party, thus, entered the Depression unified but isolated with a membership not much bigger than 10% of the combined membership of the 1919 Communist factions. Their dependence on Soviet intervention to settle disputes shaped the Party's subsequent political culture. While all Communist Parties had to adhere to Comintern policy as a condition of membership, the CPUSA usually maintained less independence from Soviet direction than many other Communist parties.
  American Communists expanded their influence in the 1930s by energetic agitation for the unemployed, industrial unions, civil rights, and antifascism, especially after the shift in Comintern policy from the highly sectarian ultra-revolutionary Third Period (1927-1935) to the antifascist alliance of the Popular Front (1935-39). By 1939 they had about 75,000 members and several hundred thousand fellow travelers. The Hitler-Stalin Pact of 1939 undermined their political credibility, especially among their not insubstantial base among intellectuals and cultural producers. During the wartime alliance with the Soviet Union they regained lost membership but not the level of moral authority they had enjoyed in some circles during the Popular Front. Perhaps that is why they were so quickly politically isolated at the beginning of the Cold War. However, despite the travails of McCarthyism, the Party maintained at least a third of it peak membership until the Khrushchev speech on "the crimes of the Stalin era" at the 1956 20th Soviet Party Congress. After a brief unsuccessful attempt to reinvent the Party around democratic socialism, veteran members fled leaving an aging vestige of probably less than 5,000 active members (although they claimed more) by the late 1950s.
  Throughout the Party's history, the CPUSA sought to expand its influence by organizing and participating in a broad array of single issue organizations. Some were genuine mass movements with handfuls of Communists amidst tens or even hundreds of thousand of members. Others were Potemkin villages with little more than an office and impressive looking letterhead. Typically Party members filled important leadership slots in such organizations and Party members exercised influence beyond their numbers because of their energy and their policy of acting as a disciplined voting bloc. Both Communists and their critics referred to such organizations as front organizations, although for Communists the usage reflected their notions of "united front' while for critics the word evoked "false front' as in a Hollywood movie set. For simplicity, I decided to group many publications by such front organizations in the same section with publications and other ephemera produced by the Party itself. This is not intended as an editorial position on the nature of such front organizations.
  - "Labor Committee Report" (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - What is the New Deal?, by Earl Browder (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Dimensions Volume 1 Number 1, Discussion Journal of the W.E.B. Dubois Clubs (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - United We Stand for Peace and Socialism, by Gil Green, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Puerto Rico- 'Island Paradise' of U.S. Imperialism, by Patricia Bell, February 1967 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - The Crime of El Fanguito An Open Letter to President Truman on Puerto Rico, by William Z. Foster, April 1948 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - Report of the Fifth National Convention of the Young Communist League of U.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - No Jobs Today, A Story of a Young Worker in Pictures, by Phil Bard (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - Peace or War, The People against the Warmakers!, by Eugene Dennis, May 1946 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - New Program of the CPUSA, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - Reconversion, by George Morris, September 1945 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - The Menace of American Imperialism, by William Z. Foster, October 1945 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - The Crisis of U.S. Capitalism and the Fight-Back, Gus Hall (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - The Meaning of the 9-Party Communist Conference, by William Z. Foster, November 1947 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - Horizons of the Future, For a Socialist America, by Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, December 1959 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - The American Way to Jobs, Peace, Equal Rights and Democracy, September 1954 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - The Communist Party & How it Works, A Hand Book on its Organization & Functioning, March 1976 (Box 2, Folder 146)
  - "Forge Fighting Unity Against the Wall Street Warmakers and the Exploiters of the Southern Masses", by Jim Jackson, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 147)
  - The Constitution and By-Laws of the Communist Party of the United States of America, August 1938 (Box 2, Folder 148)
  - "History Will be Made at the Stadium Sun., Sept. 24th" (Box 2, Folder 149)
  - "On Certain Aspects of Bourgeois Nationalism" Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 150)
  - "An American People's Program to End Poverty and Unemployment in the U.S.", Economic Program of the Communist Party, U.S.A. (Box 2, Folder 151)
  - Economic Crises (Box 2, Folder 152)
  - Proceedings (Abridged) of the 16th National Convention of the Communist Party, U.S.A., May 1957 (Box 2, Folder 153)
  - What is Socialism?, by Ernst Fischer (Box 2, Folder 154)
  - Thesis and Resolutions for the Seventh National Convention of the Communist Party of U.S.A., by Central Committee Plenum (Box 2, Folder 155)
  - "Congressional Election Platform of the Communist Party" (Box 2, Folder 156)
  - Acceptance Speeches (Box 2, Folder 157)
  - "Vote Straight Communist" (Box 2, Folder 158)
  - "Smash the Bosses Hunger Program", Fight for Unemployment Insurance, Cleveland Communist Election Platform, I.O. Ford for Mayor (Box 2, Folder 159)
  - How to Make Your Vote Count, The Communist Position on the Issues and Candidates in the 1948 Elections, by George Morris, October 1948 (Box 2, Folder 160)
  - "Southside Election Rally" (Box 2, Folder 161)
  - "Workers of Hamtrack Vote Communist- Against Hunger and Fascism" (Box 2, Folder 162)
  - "The Platform of the Class Struggle", National Platform of the Workers (Communist) Party, 1928 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Vote for John Makowski", Communist Candidate for Council- Ward 21 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Vote Communist Workers of the World United, "Congressional Platform of the Communist Party, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "Support the People's Cause..." (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "McCarthyism and the New Jersey Elections" (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "1948 Election Platform of the Communist Party" (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - "1952 Election Platform of the Communist Party" (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "The Communist Election Platform 1936" (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "What the People of Texas Need", The Communist Program for the Lone Star State (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "The 1940 Elections, How the People Can Win", By Earl Browder, May, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "America Needs Earl Browder", By A.B. Magil (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "Milestones in the History of the Communist Party", By Alex Bittelman, August, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 12)